John Clarke Slater Papers 1908-1976 Mss.B.SL2p
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Notes and bound volumes, 1926-1970; 29 linear feet
  - Slater, John Clarke. Quantum theory project; Contains correspondence, articles, Sanibel Island conference materials (U. of Fla.), etc., February-August 1970.
    - The self-consistent field X-alpha cluster method for polyatomic molecules and solids; Manuscript and page proof., 1971.
    - Solid state and molecular physicists.
    - Solid state and molecular theory. (9 copies). Copy 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, incomplete, page proof. Also: Proposal for renewal of research grant. [Sub-title is: A scientific biography], 1973, 1972.
    - Space groups and wave/function symmetry.
    - Statistical exchange and the total energy of a crystal.
    - Statistical exchange correlation correction in the self-consistent field; (2 copies) in Manuscript; Xerox copy also). Galley copy. 4 copies in all., 1971.
    - -Suggestions from solid-state theory regarding molecular calculations, 1965.
    - Summer Research Conference on theoretical chemistry, June 1972.
    - Symmetry and energy bonds in crystals. Manuscript and part of page proof.
    - Slater, J.C. (?). [Thermal Conductivity of Superconductors].
    - Thermodynamics, with P. W. Bridgman; (used as a basis for Introduction to chemical physics), 1930-1931.
    - University of Florida. Computer center, March-April 1965; April 1966-July 1967; 1969-1970.
    - University of Florida. The Graduate School. Degree requirements materials, 1964-1965.
    - University of Florida. Quantum theory project; Contains correspondence, articles, Sanibel Island conference materials, etc., February-August 1969; September 1969-January 1970; January-May 1973.
    - The vector potential in the X-alpha method, 1973.; (2 copies)
    - The water molecule.
    - The water molecule and miscellaneous manuscripts.
    - Work notebooks; vols. 1-133 incomplete., 1944-1976.
    - The X-alpha-SCF methods in chemical physics. Xerox
  - United States Air Force Office of Scientific Research. Massachusetts Institute of Technology National Magnet Laboratory. Quarterly technical report.
  - University of Florida. Assisting the University of Florida Computing Center to expand facilities. [Research proposal], 1965.
    - University senate; Minutes; Incomplete., 1965-1967.
    - Winter Institute in quantum chemistry solid-state physics and quantum biology, 1966-1967.
  - Williams, A. R. Multiple scattering by non-muffin-tin potential, 1973.
  - Wolfe, Hugh Campbell. On the principle of microscopic reversibility in the kinetic theory, 1929.
  - Wood, John H. Eigenvalue summary for nickle, 1968.
    - Quantity Eav for nickle, 1968.
- Series III. Card files, n.d.; 3 lin. feet
  Card index to reprints held by Slater and addresses.
- Series IV. Drawings, n.d.; 2 lin. feet
  - Drawings, n.d.; 22 items; Slater, John C., (John Clarke), 1900-1976 (Box 1 of 2)
  - Drawings, n.d.; 13 items; Slater, John C., (John Clarke), 1900-1976 (Box 2 of 2)
- Series V. MIT. Solid State and Molecular Theory Group. Quarterly Reports #1-73, 1951-1970; 2 lin. feet
- Photographs, A selection of photographs available from the John Clarke Slater papers.
  - Catherine C. Slater with Children, ca. 1910; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length group portrait of Catherine Slater with children John Clarke and Eleanor Chapin Slater.
  - John R. Slater, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 view portrait of John R. Slater, father of John Clarke Slater.
  - John Clarke Slater and John R. Slater, June 1926, 1926 June; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Slater standing outside beside his father.
  - Slater Wedding Party, June 1926, 1926 June; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length group wedding portrait of John Clarke Slater and family.
  - John Clarke Slater and Helen Frankenfeld Slater, at Pultneyville, New York, 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of John and Helen Slater sitting near a lake with a dog licking Helen's face.
  - John Clarke Slater, ca. 1925; 1.0 Photograph(s); Formal portrait of Slater.
  - John Clarke Slater, fomal portrait, ca. 1930; 1.0 Photograph(s); Formal portrait of Slater.
  - John Clarke Slater with his first child, Louise, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 length view of Slater holding child.
  - John Clarke Slater and family, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1946, 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait of Slater with family.
  - John Clarke Slater, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1946, 1946 December; 1.0 Photograph(s); Slater standing outside in snow, house in background.
  - Eleanor Chapin Slater, 1947, 1947 September; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Eleanor Slater, dressed in religious habit of a nun, standing outside.